<texts>
  <credits id="0" name="Parkersatinka “Miss Parker” Mozée-Melendres" role="Landscape art, copywriting, design" socials="Feel free to follow me at ParquitaBonita on Instagram!">Hi everyone! My name is Miss Parker, and I use she/her pronouns. I’m a Mexican-American student at PCC undergoing a transfer degree in equity and Indigenous Studies. My heritages are Sugpiaq, Ndé Bizaa’, Iberian, and Western and Northern European. Also as a transgender and disabled student, decolonizing the frameworks surrounding environmentalism is important to me. I want to sincerely thank Bards for working on this project with me, as well as the BIPOC voices who have shared their Knowledge with us for this project. Thank you!</credits>
  <credits id="1" name="Bards Myrick" role="Code-writing, web development, design" socials="Find me @SingingHobbit on Twitter, or Bardsichord on bandcamp">Hello! My name is Bards, and I use they/them/fae/faer pronouns. I’m an American music student at PCC, soon transferring to PSU for theater directing and design (I suppose I do the creative coding on the side, hah!). My heritages are Norwegian, Swedish, Welsh, and Northern European. I am trans, non-binary, and disabled, and I hope to always be in the process of re-understanding and practicing decolonization, both for myself and in broader contexts. Thank you to Miss Parker for this amazing collaboration experience, and thank you to the Disabled BIPOC who have created so many accessible works and resources about these topics.</credits>
  <forest title="White Veganism">
    <section id="2" reference="Superfoods Aren't Real. So Why Do Americans Believe In Them? — by Alex Berezow" url="https://www.acsh.org/news/2019/01/03/superfoods-arent-real-so-why-do-americans-believe-them-13704">There’s an illimitable amount of food combinations you can consume to receive the necessary molecules your body needs to live. “Superfoods” are a marketing scam taking advantage of consumers in the culture of quick-fix capitalism, often in the form of oppressive agricultural and consumer models forced on BIPOC communities.</section>
    <section id="3" reference="It’s Time We Decolonized White Veganism by — by Raphael Miller" url="https://www.litwi.org/blog/its-time-we-decolonized-white-veganism">Veganism has long been an action of resistance, as well as an empowering connection to cultural roots in BIPOC communities. When agents of white supremacy intensely commodify veganism, we see that it becomes less accessible to BIPOC communities.</section>
    <section id="4" reference="What Is White Veganism? — by @QueerBrownVegan" url="https://queerbrownvegan.com/what-is-white-veganism/">Very often we see veganism from a white perspective, which usually attributes the diet solely to animal “liberation.” This separates the deeply spiritual and important reasons many Black and Indigenous cultures have practiced this diet, which was long before the term “vegan” was created and adopted by colonial societies. It’s important to include BIPOC perspectives to help solve the issues veganism attempts to address and then some.</section>
    <section id="5" reference="coming soon!" url="javascript:redraw();"> </section>
  </forest>
  <ice title="Seasonality and Climate Change">
    <section id="6" reference="Indian time: time, seasonality, and culture in Traditional Ecological Knowledge of climate change — by Samantha Chisholm Hatfield et al." url="https://ecologicalprocesses.springeropen.com/articles/10.1186/s13717-018-0136-6">There are 365 days in the Gregorian calendar - the one most of the world uses today. There are four quarters within a year of this calendar that show changes in climate and daylight hours. These quarters are known as the four seasons. The flow of time is observed differently in many Indigenous cultures. When seasons take the shape of the local patterns of life, variations are more noticeable. This is known as Seasonality.</section>
    <section id="7" reference="Lenape Seasons — by Native American Heritage Programs" url="https://lenapeprograms.info/lenape-delaware-indian-resources/lenape-seasons/">Indigenous communities utilize Seasonality differently to fit the needs of their unique environments - this promotes the biodiversity and sustainability of their lands, and makes Indigenous communities more sensitive to changes in the environment.</section>
    <section id="8" reference="Climate Change — by the United Nations Department of Economic and Social Affairs: Indigenous Peoples" url="https://www.un.org/development/desa/indigenouspeoples/climate-change.html">Indigenous Peoples have been the most substantial advocates that climate change can be witnessed and needs to be prepared for. The threats of climate change affect Indigenous communities on a larger scale, despite these communities producing the least greenhouse emissions. Many problems in the realm of climate change cannot be addressed appropriately without Indigenous Peoples involved in helping to find solutions.</section>
    <section id="9" reference="coming soon!" url="javascript:redraw();"> </section>
  </ice>
  <beach title="Straw Bans and Single-Use Plastics">
    <section id="10" reference="(video) Banning Straws Hurts People // The Last Straw! — by Jessica Kellgren-Fozard" url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4IBH0pcKzlY">Many disabled people rely on the mobility and design of plastic straws to accommodate their needs. With plastic straws making up only ≈ 0.025% of all metric tons of plastic in the oceans and their coastlines, straw bans ultimately end up hurting individuals while failing to hold corporations accountable for their massive contribution to plastics in the ocean.</section>
    <section id="11" reference="Colonialism, the climate crisis, and the need to center Indigenous voices — by Deniss Martinez and Ans Irfan" url="https://www.ehn.org/indigenous-people-and-climate-change-2655479728.html">Banning plastics is a necessary step in healing the damage done by colonialism. Without proper and affordable replacements for everyone, banning the plastic straw was and remains the irresponsible choice.</section>
    <section id="12" reference="Plan to ban single-use plastics has First Nations with long-term drinking water advisories worried — by Rhiannon Johnson" url="https://www.cbc.ca/news/indigenous/single-use-plastic-bottle-water-advisories-first-nations-1.5176370">The effects of colonialism have forced many Indigenous communities to rely on single-use plastics to consume clean water and other necessities. The conversation about how to tackle plastic waste must include Indigenous and Black voices to be successful. Banning single-use plastics punishes the individual/community instead of targeting the larger issues on mass production and waste by companies and corporations.</section>
    <section id="13" reference="(video) Neskantaga Chief describes emotional toll of water crisis on community members — Global News Canada" url="https://globalnews.ca/video/7414316/neskantaga-chief-describes-emotional-toll-of-water-crisis-on-community-members/">The water crisis has especially affected Indigenous communities in extreme ways. Rationing bottles of water is a tactic utilized simply because there is no access to clean water. Banning single-use plastics without first making sure our Indigenous families and communities have clean water is a form of genocide. 
</section>
  </beach>
  <fire title="Settler Environmentalist Myths">
    <section id="14" reference="How racist myths built the population growth bogey-man — by Hiba Ahmad" url="https://www.globaljustice.org.uk/blog/2019/03/how-racist-myths-built-population-growth-bogey-man/">Overpopulation (coming soon!)</section>
    <section id="15" reference="When conservation provides a cover for anti-Indigenous sentiments — by Tristan Ahtone" url="https://www.hcn.org/articles/tribal-affairs-conservation-provides-a-cover-for-anti-indigenous-sentiments-stolen-land">Conservation/preservation (coming soon!)</section>
    <section id="16" reference="Environmentalism’s Wilderness Myth — by Mikaila Davis" url="https://www.platformmagazine.me/stories/environmentalisms-wilderness-myth">“Untouched wilderness” (coming soon!)</section>
    <section id="17" reference="Return the National Parks to the Tribes — by David Treuer" url="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2021/05/return-the-national-parks-to-the-tribes/618395/">National Parks (coming soon!)</section>
  </fire>
</texts>